datapine.com 2019-02-13

# Privacy Policy | datapine

**Privacy Policy – Effective as of May 24, 2018** **DATAPINE GMBH, Friedelstrasse 27, 12047 Berlin**

DATAPINE is aware of the importance of protecting your personal information and is committed to ensuring that your information is processed responsibly and in accordance with applicable data protection laws (GDPR) in all countries in which DATAPINE conducts business.

This Privacy Policy describes DATAPINE's general privacy practices with regards to the processing, collection, usage, and disclosure of personal information of users and others by our customers, business partners, suppliers, and other companies with whom DATAPINE conducts business. This privacy policy describes how DATAPINE handles information that can be used, directly or indirectly, to identify individuals ("personal information").

**General Information** **What does this privacy policy apply to?**

This Privacy Policy applies to personal information that you provide to DATAPINE or is derived from personal information as described below. The use of cookies or other web tracking technologies as well as the information collected thereby is subject to the information and options provided by the Cookie Consent Manager, whereby the CIVIC Consent Manager can be found on the respective website.

**What does DATAPINE do with my personal data?**

DATAPINE will process the personal data only as it is outlined by this Privacy Policy and as it is described herein.

**Why do I have to provide personal information?**

Granting consent or providing personal data is hereunder entirely voluntary. In general, failure to give consent or provide personal information will not adversely affect you. However, there are situations in which DATAPINE cannot operate without certain personal information; for example, personal information might be needed to process your orders or to give you access to a complimentary Test-Account (Free-Trial) or newsletter. In such cases, DATAPINE cannot provide you with the requested service without the relevant personal data.

**Usage of the service by children**

This website is not intended for anyone under the age of 18. If you are under 18, you may not use this website and the offered services.

**Links to other websites**

This website may contain links to third-party websites (that is, websites of companies that are not part of DATAPINE). DATAPINE is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of websites outside of DATAPINE. For this reason, we recommend that you carefully read the privacy statements of these third-party websites.

**Introduction**

There are a variety of reasons why you would choose to provide us with your personal information. For example, you may decide to give us your name and contact information so that we can communicate with you, place an order, provide you with a subscription or service, or otherwise conduct business with you if you are a supplier or business partner. We may receive details from you about your credit card if you wish to purchase something from DATAPINE, or we will receive your CV in connection with a job advertisement you are applying for. If you ask us not to use your data after processing your request for further contact, we will respect your request and delete your data.

**Registration**

When requesting information, downloading publications, registering for a live or virtual event, or requesting a trial of our software products, you may be asked to provide your name, business contact information, and other information related to your request. Some of DATAPINE products and services may require unique registration, specifically for the provision of our products or services.

We use this information in connection with your request and to communicate with you. In most cases, you can also identify this information when you visit our websites. Your information will be stored for possible future interactions with you.

**Information for Business Partners**

If you are or are acting as a DATAPINE Business Partner, you can access DATAPINE websites created specifically for DATAPINE Business Partners. The personal data transmitted by accessing these web pages will be used to generally manage and develop the business relationships between DATAPINE and you, your represented business partner and the DATAPINE business partners. For example, this may mean that your personal information is being used to send you details about DATAPINE Business Partner programs. In addition, certain information (in accordance with any existing secrecy obligations) may be shared with other Business Partners or DATAPINE customers or potential DATAPINE customers. In connection with a particular transaction or program, you may be contacted through customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.

**Human Resources**

In connection with an application or request, whether made on a DATAPINE website or in any other way, DATAPINE will receive personal information from you, such as a CV. DATAPINE may use this personal information within the company for the purpose of deciding on employment or responding to the request. If you ask us not to use your data after processing your request for further contact, we will respect your request and delete your data.

**Why and how is your personal information collected and used?**

Your personal data may be collected by us for various purposes, as described below.

**Access to websites and other online services and their usage**

When you open one of our websites or use an online service, information might be recorded as it is necessary to operate the website and comply with technical and legal requirements associated with the operation of our website, such as: passwords, IP address (anonymized) and web browser settings. Information about your activities during your visit to the respective website might also be collected in order to personalize your experience on our websites, such as your preferences and settings, and to collect statistical information in order to improve and develop our websites, products and services.

Our web servers, like most servers on the internet, store each access to our website in a log file. The following data is collected:

  * IP address of the requesting computer
  * Date and time of access
  * Name and URL of the downloaded file
  * Volume of transmitted data
  * Confirmation of whether the request was successful
  * Data identifying the browser and operating system
  * Website from which our site was accessed

This data is required for the use of the website (connection establishment, data transfer). We retain this information for purposes of system security, for technical administration of the network infrastructure as well as to improve the website, for a maximum of 24 hours.

Only system administrators have access to this data. An assessment of this data only takes place in case of justified suspicion due to an attack on our network infrastructure or an improper use of our services.

**Your use of DATAPINE Services**

We collect information about your use of DATAPINE Services to perform product functions, improve your experience, customize our interaction with you, inform our customers about the overall Services, provide support, and improve our products and services. Details regarding the technologies used by DATAPINE, the personal data collected by DATAPINE, and the control or disabling of tracking functions as cookies are set out below.

**Cookies**

In order for the offered services to work properly, we sometimes store small files - called cookies - on your device. This is common on most major websites.

**What are cookies and why are they used?**

A cookie is a piece of data that sends a web page to your web browser to store on your system as an identifier that identifies your system. Often, cookies are only used to measure usage (such as number of visitors and duration of a visit) and effectiveness (such as topics the visitor is most interested in) on a web page and to facilitate navigation. They are not associated with personally identifiable information but are occasionally used to personalize a known visitor's web page experience by associating profile information or user preferences. Over time, this information provides valuable insights that help improve the user experience on a web page.

Cookies are usually divided into session cookies and persistent cookies. With session cookies you can navigate the website in an efficient manner, whereby the cookies log your way through the individual web pages, so that you are not prompted for information that you have already entered during the same visit to the website in question. Completion of a transaction will be needed. Session cookies are stored in temporary storage and deleted when the web browser is closed. Persistent cookies, on the other hand, store user settings for the current visit as well as for future visits to the website. They are stored on your hard disk and will continue to be valid when you restart the web browser.

**What types of cookies does DATAPINE use?**

 **1) Necessary Cookies**

These cookies are mandatory for the basic functions of the website. For example, they guarantee a secure login or registration for a free trial of our software.

These cookies can only be deactivated by means of your individual browser settings, at which point you cannot use a large number of functions of this website.

**2) Functional Cookies**

These cookies enable us to analyze website usage so that we can measure and improve their performance. This helps us to constantly improve the user experience on our website.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Use includes the Universal Analytics operating mode. This makes it possible to assign data, sessions and interactions across multiple devices to a pseudonymous user ID.

Google Analytics uses cookies that are stored on your computer and that allow an analysis of the use of the website by you. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. DATAPINE has activated Google's IP anonymization so that your IP address will be truncated by Google within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area prior to transmission. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. The IP address provided by Google Analytics as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other Google data. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. In these purposes, our legitimate interest lies in the data processing. The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is § 15 para. 3 TMG or Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The data sent by us and linked to cookies, user IDs (eg user ID) or advertising IDs will be automatically deleted after 14 months. The deletion of data whose retention period has been reached is done automatically once a month. For more information about Terms of Use and Privacy, please visit <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html> or <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en>.

You can prevent the storage of cookies using the settings of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible. You may also prevent the collection of the cookie-generated and website-related information (including your IP address) to Google and the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing a [Browser-Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Opt-out cookies prevent future collection of your data when you visit a website. To prevent Universal Analytics tracking across devices, you must opt-out on all systems you use. If you click here, the opt-out cookie will be set: Deactivate Google Analytics.

Google Tag Manager is a solution that enables marketers to manage website tags from one interface. The Tag Manager tool itself (which implements the tags) is a cookie-less domain and does not collect personally identifiable information. The tool triggers other tags, which may collect data. Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If disabled at the domain or cookie level, it will remain in effect for all tracking tags implemented with Google Tag Manager.

**3) Marketing Cookies**

These cookies are used by us and advertising agencies to provide you with advertisements and content that are relevant to your interests.

**Cookie Control**

You can control and/or deactivate cookies at will. When you visit our website, you have the ability to set your preferences regarding cookies and other similar technologies by using the options and tools provided to you either by your web browser or by DATAPINE at the bottom left browser corner.

You can delete all cookies stored on your computer and set most browsers to prevent the storage of cookies. By doing so, you may have to change your settings manually every time you visit a page, and you may be bothered by some other limitations. You can find information about the corresponding settings of your browser in the help function of your browser.

In addition, you can control the use of different types of cookies through our Cookie Consent Manager at any time. First, this will be displayed on your first visit to our website. Then you can customize your cookie preferences in the lower left area of your screen by clicking on the appropriate navigation menu. The use of cookie preferences will not delete cookies that are already on your device. To do so, you need to delete these cookies manually through the settings of your web browser.

**Answering your inquiries regarding information, orders or support**

When you contact us (online or offline) in connection with a request for information, a product or service order, the provision of support or participation in a forum, or the use of any other social computing tool, we collect the information, we need to fulfill your request, give you access to the appropriate product or service, provide you with support, and contact you. For example, you may include your name and contact information, details of your request, agreement with us, and fulfillment, provision, and billing of your order, as well as information from customer satisfaction surveys. This information is stored for administrative purposes, to protect our rights and in connection with our relationship with you.

If you provide your name and contact information to register for such a request, this registration may be used to identify you when you visit our websites. To order most services and products, you must have registered a DATAPINE account.

**Contacting employees of our customers, potential customers, partners and suppliers**

As part of our relationship with customers, potential customers, partners and suppliers, you may provide us with information, for example business-related contact information (such as name, business contact information, position or title of employees, contractors, consultants, and authorized users) for the purposes of contract management, fulfillment of the contract, the provision of products and services, the provision of support, the billing and management of the services or the business relationship.

**Visitor information**

We register individuals who visit our locations (name, identification, and business contact information) for security, personal and property protection, and regulatory compliance.

**Marketing**

Most of the information we collect about you comes from our direct interactions with you. When registering for an event, we may collect information (online or offline) about the registration, but also during an event, such as the event organization through participation in individual modules and survey results. We combine the personal information collected to develop aggregated analytics and business intelligence to conduct our business and for marketing purposes. You can choose to receive information about our products and services by e-mail, telephone or mail, or sign up for a subscription. If you visit our websites or use our services, we may provide you with personalized information. You can opt-out of receiving personalized communications at any time by sending an email to [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com).

If we indicate that we use your personal information in connection with a request, order, transaction or agreement (or preparation) or to provide you with services that you have requested (e.g. a website), we do so, because it is necessary for the fulfillment of an agreement with you.

If we indicate that we use your personal information in connection with marketing, the improvement or development of our products or services, for security reasons, or because of legal regulations that are unrelated to your agreement or requirement, we do so based on our legitimate interest, the legitimate interest of a third party, or with your consent.

DATAPINE may use the personal information you provide to DATAPINE and the personally identifiable information we collect indirectly for marketing purposes, e.g. to keep you informed about events, products, services and solutions that DATAPINE sells and that can complement an existing product portfolio (product recommendations).

However, before we use your personal information, you have the ability to determine whether or not your information may be used for such purposes. If you no longer wish to receive marketing materials from DATAPINE, simply follow the unsubscribe instructions in our emails, let us know when we contact you, or contact us directly (for more information see the "Questions about this statement and contacting DATAPINE" section at the bottom of this page).

Some of our offers or events may be offered under a co-branded brand or may be offered by DATAPINE and third parties such as business partners and solution providers who use, resell, or supplement DATAPINE products or services. Offers and events under a common brand clearly indicate that such a partnership exists. When you register for these offers or events, you should be aware that your personal information may also be collected and shared by those third parties. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with each privacy policy to see how your information is used there.

**Usage of personal data**

The following sections describe how DATAPINE may use your personal information.

**Fulfillment of your transaction requests**

If you request product information, service, a call back, or special DATAPINE marketing materials, we might use the personal information you submit to fulfill your request. To facilitate your request, we may exchange your data with third parties who are involved in order processing, as for example DATAPINE business partners, financial institutions, mail-order companies, postal services or public authorities (e.g. customs authorities). You may also be contacted for customer satisfaction surveys or for market research purposes.

**Personalization of your experience on our websites**

We may use personal information that is collected to personalize your experience on our websites and services for you; for example, to provide you with content that you may be interested in and to facilitate navigation on our websites. This information may also be used to improve our websites.

**Provision of support**

We may use your personal information to support products or services you have purchased through us, such as product updates or fixes. Your information may be combined with information from other interactions with you to provide you with even more useful suggestions regarding product usage and support.

You may also be offered "live chat" sessions on our web pages to assist you in navigating our web pages or in our forums and blogs. The personal information you provide to us during these sessions or in these forums will be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

As part of providing technical support, we may have access to your data that you have provided to us or that is within your account if you provided a valid login. This information may include information about you, your employees, customers, business partners, or suppliers of your business. This privacy policy also applies to the access to or the processing of this personal information.

**Storage of data**

Your personal data will be stored by DATAPINE for as long as it is necessary in order to fulfill the purposes for which it is processed or for other valid reasons (e.g. to comply with our legal obligations, to settle disputes or to enforce our contractual agreements).

We will retain your registration information for as long as your account is active or for as long as necessary to provide you services. If we should no longer use your registration information for service delivery, please contact us at [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com). In connection with DATAPINE Services, the use of which you have been authorized by a DATAPINE customer who has commissioned this service with DATAPINE, your registration information may be stored in order to meet certain requirements of this DATAPINE customer.

**Transmission of personal data**

As a global company, we may share your personal information with our locations worldwide in accordance with this privacy policy and transmit it to DATAPINE locations in other countries.

Locations controlled by DATAPINE will only be granted access to personal information if they have a legitimate interest and are required to do so. In individual cases, DATAPINE works with subcontractors in different countries to collect, use, analyze or otherwise process personal information on behalf of DATAPINE.

Where appropriate, or based on your consent, DATAPINE may also share your personal information with selected partners who help us deliver products or services to you or the company you work for or to meet your needs. When selecting our subcontractors and partners, their data processing processes are taken into account.

Should DATAPINE choose to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize companies in certain countries, such a transaction may include disclosure of personal information to potential or actual purchasers or receipt of such information from sellers. It is common practice to require appropriate protection of personal data in such transactions.

Please note that it may be possible, in certain situations, for personal data to be disclosed to public authorities on the basis of a legal or regulatory order or for compliance with the law. We may also share your personal information to protect the rights and property of DATAPINE and DATAPINE Business Partners, suppliers, customers, or third parties, if there are reasonable grounds to believe that such rights or property have been or may be adversely affected.

**Security and Quality of information**

It is our concern to protect your personal information and to ensure its accuracy. DATAPINE has implemented reasonable physical, administrative and technical safeguards to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use and disclosure. For example, certain particularly sensitive personal information (e.g., credit card information) is encrypted when transmitted over the Internet. We also require our suppliers and partners to protect this information from unauthorized access, use and disclosure.

**Protection of the rights and property of DATAPINE and third parties**

We may also use or share your personal information to protect the rights and property of DATAPINE and its business partners, suppliers, customers or other third parties where there are reasonable grounds to believe that such rights or property have been or may be adversely affected. In addition, DATAPINE reserves the right to disclose your personal information where required by law and if we believe that disclosure is to protect the rights of DATAPINE or any third party, or to comply with any legal or regulatory order or legal process required on our website.

**Monitor or record calls, chats, and other interactions**

Certain online transactions may include contacting you by phone or vice versa. This may also include online chats. Please note that DATAPINE generally monitors these interactions for staff training or quality assurance, and in some cases records or maintains evidence of a particular transaction or interaction.

**Safekeeping period**

Personal data will not be stored longer than necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it is processed, including compliance with legal or regulatory obligations (such as auditing, billing, and statutory retention periods), litigation, and justification, to exercise or defend legal claims in the countries in which we do business.

Because circumstances may vary depending on the context and services, specific notification may provide more detailed information about applicable retention periods.

**Newsletter**

Registered users can order the DATAPINE newsletter separately. In this case, DATAPINE will use the user-supplied name and the email address provided by the user for sending the newsletter. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the newsletter or by e-mailing [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com).

**Data Processing Agreement**

If DATAPINE receives access to data that represents personal data in the sense of § 3 Abs. 1 BDSG, the conclusion of a separate data processing agreement may be required, depending on the legal system that applies to the user. This applies in particular to users who are subject to European data protection law. DATAPINE will provide you with an appropriate agreement in this case, which the user may request by emailing [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com).

**Your rights**

You may request information regarding your personal information, updating or rectification. You also have the right to object to direct mail. Please contact [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com). The processing of your personal data is subject to the regulations of the DSGVO/GDPR.

Thus, you may object to the processing of your personal data for reasons that arise from your particular situation. Within the framework of the GDPR you also have the right to request the deletion, restrict the processing of, and the transfer of your personal data. Please contact [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com).

**Right of appeal**

If you believe that the processing of your personal data violates the applicable data protection laws, you can file a complaint:

1) Contact directly DATAPINE under [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com).

2) With the responsible supervisory authority. Names and contact information of the competent supervisory authorities in the European Union can be found at [http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm.](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm)

**Questions about this statement and contacting DATAPINE**

If you have a question about this privacy policy or about the processing of personal data by DATAPINE, please send an e-mail to [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com). Your message will be sent to the appropriate member of the DATAPINE Privacy Team, such as data protection officers or members of their teams.

You can also reach us at the following address:

DATAPINE GmbH

Friedelstraße 27

12047 Berlin

Deutschland

Under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (DSGVO), the current Data Protection Officer is:

René Rautenberg

René Rautenberg GmbH

Radlkoferstrasse 2

81373 München

In certain cases, you may choose to view or edit your personal information online. If you do not have access to your personal information online or you require a copy of certain information provided to DATAPINE, or if you find a false information that requires correction, please contact us.

If you no longer wish to receive marketing emails or product recommendations from DATAPINE, please email [privacy@datapine.com](mailto:privacy@datapine.com).

**Validity of the privacy policy**

Translated versions of the contracts and policies are provided only to facilitate understanding of the German version. The provision of translations of contracts and policies is not intended to create any other legally binding agreement, and the translations are not a substitute for the validity of the German versions. In the case of contradictions or conflicts the German version takes precedence over the provisions in other languages.

**Changes to the DATAPINE Privacy Policy**

DATAPINE reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time to adapt it to the functionality of the Website and the Service. If any changes are made to this Privacy Policy, this Privacy Policy will be given a new date. Visitors to the website are subject to the latest version of the privacy policy. Existing customers are advised of any changes to the privacy policy.
